Ricardo Moura Vargas | Frontend Developer

I consider my self an honest and hardworking person. I am creative and I love to learn, I'm always looking for opportunities to learn new technologies and ideas. I'm also love to meet people and new places, this curiosity lead me to move to Ireland where I lived and studied english for 3 years.

As a developer, I've been working with web development over 6 years and I also have 2 years of experience developing native android apps. Nowadays I focused in front-end development.

Website: https://ricardomvargas.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/ricardomvargas Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardo-m-vargas/ Phone (whatsapp): + 55 41 99128-8920 E-mail: mvargas.ricardo@gmail.com

Tech skills

- Web development with: HTML, CSS, SASS, Material UI and Bootstrap.
- Programming interfaces and app's with: Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, React-router, React-intl, styled components and axios.
- Desing: Illustrador.
- Basic backend development experience with: .NET/C#, PHP and Node JS.
- Other tools: git, yarn/npm, Jira and Bitbucket.

Soft Skills

- Good communications skills.
- Focused in solving problems.
- Flexible: I'm not afraid to leave my comfort zone to help or learn.
- Native portuguese speaker with advanced english level.
- Team work spirit.
- · Mind opened and respectful.
- I'm take responsibility for my acts and I'm not shy to admit my mistakes.

Education

May 2020	Learning TypeScript	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Apr. 2020	Learning ECMA Script 6 (2016)	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Mar. 2020	Bootstrap 4 Essential Training	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Apr. 2020	React: React Router	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Mar. 2020	Node.js Essential Training	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Jan. 2020	Vue.js Essential Training	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Jan. 2020	PHP with MySQL Essential Training: 1 The Basics	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Jan. 2020	React: SPAs	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Oct. 2019	React.js: Building an Interface (2019)	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Sep. 2019	React for Web Designers (2018)	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
Aug. 2019	Learning React	Linkedin Learning, online (*)
2017 - 2018	English Language (Advanced)	Liffey College, Dublin - Ireland
2016 - 2017	English Language (Intermediate)	Liffey College, Dublin - Ireland
2015 - 2016	English Language (Basic)	English Studio, Dublin - Ireland
2012 - 2015	System Information (not finished)	Centro Universitário de Vila Velha
2013	Android App Development Essential Trainning	Lynda.com
2013	Developing android apps	Visure Treinamentos, Vitória
2012	Developing Web Applications Using VS 2008	Mindworks, Vitória
2007	High School	CIE, Governador Valadares

(*) Certificates are visible in my linkedin profile.

Work Experience

Front end developer | Apr. 2020 to current date | Agrotis

Working as React developer building new features to the grain storage module.

- Doing brainstorming to defining the sprint tasks.
- Doing daily meetings to check what was done.
- Creating new features and fixing bugs.
- Re-write class base components to functional components.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I work with: React, Redux, redux-form, react-hook-form, styled component, Material UI, react router, axios, Typescript, npm/yarn, git, bitbucket and Jira.

Web and Mobile Developer | Sep. 2014 - Feb. 2016 | PrimeLan Tecnologia

Creating android app's, websites and CMS by demand. I created the Vitória(ES) city official android app and an API for bus prediction using google maps.

- Doing brainstorming to planning the projects.
- Meeting clients to gathering information.
- Creating and consuming web services.
- Creating web sites, Android app's and CMS systems by demand.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: Java, Android SDK, Google Maps API, PHP, MySql, HTML, CSS, Javascript, - JQuery, RESTfull API, JSON, Git, Adobe Fireworks e Adobe Illustrator.

Full Stack Developer | Nov. 2012 - Sep. 2014 | Megawork

I worked with .Net 3.0 and C# to created a suppliers pricing web application that integrates with SAP. Also developed web sites and CMS by demand and I had some basic ABAP training.

- Developing web applications with .Net/C#.
- Creating services to connect and consuming data from SAP.
- Working as front-end to developing web sites.
- Doing meetings with clients and managers to gather projects details.
- Doing meetings with the web team to define project details.
- Creating web applications with Cristal Report.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 3.5, C#, SQLServer, PostGreSQL, SAP .Net Connector, .Net Web Services, SAP, ABAP, Java, Android SDK, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Git e SVN.

.Net Developer | Feb. 2012 - Nov. 2012 | Phidelis Tecnologia

As .Net developer I worked in a web application for managing schools and universities, correcting bug's, creating custom features and training users.

- Developing custom features for clients.
- Fixing bugs reported by the clients.
- Working with the development team to create new features and updating the application version.
- Upgrading code to use .Net 3.5 features.
- Updating interfaces with Javascript libraries to improve users experience.
- Training new users, helping clients with custom and new features.
- Creating new database tables and updating data.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 2.0 - 3.5, C#, SQLServer, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery/outros, e Windows Team Foudation.

.Net Developer | Jun. 2011 - Feb. 2012 | Superius Consultoria LTDA

At Superius I was part of the web team that was building ERP system using .Net 3.0, C#, DevExpress and Entity Framework.

- Doing meetings with different types of managers to gathering information for developing the system modules.
- Working with the development team to analyze data and create tasks.
- Creating database tables based on the new features.
- Creating libraries and base classes for general use.
- Creating custom interfaces using DevExpress library.
- Developing all the main features and interfaces for the sales module.
- Removing DevExpress library and implement lightweight javascript libraries to improve web pages performances.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 2.0 - 3.5, C#, SQLServer, DevExpress, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery e SVN.

Junior .Net Developer | Jan. 2010 - Jul. 2011 | Vixtime

I Worked as web developer using .Net/C# for creating CMS and other systems, also created web sites by demand and helped creating a News web app. I also had a chance to play a little bit with AS3 for flash applications.

- Doing brainstorming to debate ideas about projects and campaigns.
- Doing cuts and exporting images using Adobe Fireworks.
- Creating web sites by demand with HTML, CSS e Javascript following web standards.
- Creating and customize CMS systems for clients.
- Fixing bug's and creating new features for the ESHoje News web system.
- Helping the graphic designer to implement Adobe Flash animations and features using AS3.

Tools/libs/frameworks that I worked with: ASP.Net 2.0, C#, SQLServer, HTML, CSS, Javascript (Jquery/outros), Visual Studio, Fireworks e Dreamweaver.